Presented and Distributed
by Showbox / Mediaplex
Produced by Moonlight Film
and Showbox / Mediaplex
HA JUNG-WOO
GANG DONG-WON
In 1862, during the Joseon Dynasty,
The people suffered from famine and plague,
as well as unrelenting
exploitation from corrupt officials,
as well as noblemen.
Peasant revolts were far too common.
Those captured were executed
for breaking the law,
while others fled to the woods
and lived as bandits.
Executive Producer YOU JEONG-HUN
Directed by YOON JONG-BIN
Act 1: Chusul Clan of Mt. Jiri
This is Lord Jo Won-suk's son Jo Su-in.
My father's had a stroke
and could not attend,
pardon me for coming in his place.
Hope he recovers soon.
It's ivory.
My father's small gesture...
He sincerely congratulates
you on your 60th.
Tell him his gift is happily accepted.
I brought this from China
especially for you,
it's called a telescope.
It allows you to see things
far in the distance.
Extend it out.
Let me try this.
That's amazing!
The Chinese ambassador told me
that you have an eye
for precious Chinese goods.
Governor...
If you'll grant me a private audience,
good fortune will find you.
In a moment.
Of course.
You rude bastards!
Your mourning is ruining our party!
Off you go!
The dead man stopped for the scent of beef.
Don't be so stingy.
Share some of your leftover soup with us.
That is the shittiest
bullshit I've ever heard.
Dead men can't smell shit!
He died of starvation,
so if the Governor releases his spite,
good fortune will follow.
The compassion of Buddha.
Even death is not to be feared by
one who has lived wisely.
Rest in peace.
Now that it's over, get going!
Sir.
I beg you a small favor.
In his dying breath...
my father told me never to sell...
this poetry or something.
But since I can't read,
I dunno what it says.
I'd be in your debt if
you could take a look.
All right.
Tang Yin was a Chinese scholar,
painter, and poet during the Ming Dynasty.
It's... none other than Tang Yin.
Are you sure?
I've travelled to China
since childhood with my grandfather.
I'm a third generation
trader so I can tell.
This is genuine.
Tang Yin's poetry for a mere bowl of soup,
good fortune did come!
Bring out the good wine for the governor.
Also prepare some food for the pallbearers.
Yes, sir.
We mustn't drink while we're on duty.
You know how uptight this place is,
it's all from the top, so
set your worries aside.
To give you some more context,
it's said that Tang is
more valuable than the Forbidden City.
This telescope is worthless
by comparison...
- The value of this...
- Quiet!
- Let's talk inside.
- Sorry, governor.
I feel so dopey after just one drink.
You too?
What the heck?
How dare you...
You hag!
'Ethics of Governing People'
Found a good passage in the preface.
Today, those who serve the people,
serve only their own interests,
and do not fulfill their duty.
While hunger and disease
are a way of life for the people.
Civil servants are stuffing themselves
with food, silk, and jewels.
Isn't this shameful?
Isn't it indeed.
Stop this madman!
Who dares to stop
the captain of Mt. Jiri's Chusul clan?
Here they come.
Hurry up, get your weapon!
- You bitch!
- Stop right there!
I will now clearly recite your crimes.
No need for excuses.
The crimes of governor Choi are as follows!
One!
Stealing from the poor
rather than serving them!
Two!
Forced labor without any pay!
Three!
Neglecting civic duties and
wasting tax payers' money
for personal gain, and so forth.
On behalf of the populace,
we, the Chusul clan,
sentence you to death!
The compassion of Buddha.
Stop it!
It's mine! Mine!
Dae-ho
The Vicious Monk
Tae-GI
Ma-hyang
Chun-BO
Geum-San
KUNDO
Ouch!
Hurts, huh?
It's supposed to hurt.
Ow! Ouch!
It's okay, you won't die.
Look closely.
My brother is only 18 years old.
Not much older than y'all.
Wow!
You see?
Not even a flinch. But that's not all.
Ow!
Don't be a baby.
You're far from being a man!
Just watch now.
Wow!
He was also a weakling at your age.
But after eating this,
he became a strong man.
Here, here.
Take it, here.
Y'all got it? Now, your turn.
Great.
So big!
Why's your hand empty?
Nuthin' at my house.
Not even rat turds.
What's this bullshit?
Desperate times call for
desperate measures.
Go steal your mum's undies if you have to.
Go on.
That's everything?
During the Joseon era, butchers
were considered the lowest social class.
They were no better than slaves.
Dolmuchi, the butcher
Act 2: The March of the Dead
Jo Yoon
Jo Yoon, son of Naju noble Jo Won-suk,
was a natural born martial artist,
who passed high-level military exams
at the tender age of 19,
and was promoted to captain at 21.
His combat prowess was next to none.
He had mastered military tactics
and various weapons early on.
His fists smashed rocks,
his spear pierced flying birds,
and his sword sliced the light
and made rainbows.
He was a force to be reckoned with,
to say the least.
Born to a Naju courtesan in a brothel,
he was destined for
greatness or affliction,
depending on which family he was born to.
He was raised by courtesans
since his birth,
and finally met his father at the age of 8.
For a man of such stature,
you mustn't be so frugal.
I knew you weren't an ordinary woman,
but bargaining for the
life of your own son?
What a natural huckster.
His father was Lord Jo Won-suk,
a corrupt former governor
of Jeola province, who built his fortune
by exploiting his citizens.
Lady Jo, who only had 4 girls,
was threatened by the appearance of
Lord Jo's illegitimate son,
but Lord Jo only cared that
he now had a bright heir
to continue his distinguished family name.
Builds an upright character.
Very good.
But Lady Jo was a woman of
far stronger will than he thought.
In order to conceive a boy
she challenged herself to no end...
What's gotten into you?
- Honey...
- Let's do it another time.
Let go of your pants.
And defying all biological limitations...
She finally achieved her
goal at the age of 40.
It's a boy!
Thanks to his new half brother,
Jo Yoon instantly became
Ugly duckling of the family,
who felt the cruelty of life early on,
and his feelings turned
into anger and hostility.
If you ever do it again,
you'll go back to the whorehouse!
He endured the nightmare
that was his childhood.
Su-in for sale!
He's cheap!
Jo Yoon finally decided to
face his anger head on.
Mother...
You ungrateful bastard!
How dare you?
Lady Jo didn't think the boy
could've planned it alone,
and took his mother's life instead,
in addition to his attendant's
leg for good measure.
Think about what you've done.
For a tender boy of 11,
darkness was far too harsh a punishment.
Having heard of his brother's death at
the governor's 60th birthday party,
Jo Yoon left his post and
returned home after 10 years.
From the shock of her son's death,
Lady Jo also departed this world.
Now only Lord Jo and his son Jo Yoon
bear the family name.
However...
The funerals must've taken a toll on you.
Please eat something.
I don't want any, take it away.
You must get back on
your feet and lead our family.
Mother and Su-in are at peace now.
The living must go on.
I'll leave you be, father.
240 kg of meat and 150 kg of organs.
Not so much this time.
Hope you're not cheating us.
We'll weigh it later, don't mess around.
Here.
What the hell?
It's not enough?
Dolmuchi, a moment?
So hot...
Making a living in this
world ain't so easy.
Anyway...
There's... something that's bothering me.
Interested in a big score?
Wait here.
Master.
Come in.
Master, it's... an honor to meet you.
Are you the butcher who serves my house?
I am indeed, sir!
I'm always grateful of your...
How do you like your job?
Even livestock are living,
breathing creatures,
can't be easy to kill.
No, sir, not at all!
I can kill hundreds every day
If you'll give me the job.
You don't feel guilty?
I hear you can't do it
if you see its eyes right before.
That has never happened to me, master.
But I do try to kill it with one blow.
Animals do feel pain, after all.
I see.
Great to see such dedication.
Just one more question.
Have you...
only killed animals?
You're back!
Good job!
Wow, what's all this? Fell from the sky?
- Eat slowly.
- Did you eat?
I already had plenty.
Mum, I'm back!
Mum, look at this!
It's a feast!
What's going on?
What's all this?
Our bellies will explode.
Where did you get these?
Halfway up Mt. Dongak,
there is a small temple.
You'll find a delicate looking girl there.
20 in silver will be enough to
open a tavern anywhere.
It's your chance to live like a king.
This is a silly question, but...
what should I do with the girl?
Make her disappear.
Like she never existed.
I'm supposed to do what?
Just think of her as one of your livestock.
She went there to mourn
her husband's death,
but fooled around with the monks.
She's no better than a pig.
Who... are you?
Is anyone out there? Help!
What the hell?
Damn you!
You fool.
Trying to take a life for a petty sum?
She's a dirty whore who
fooled around with monks.
You stay out of this!
'Fooled around'?
Who fooled around with whom?
I may just be a butcher,
but I know how the world works!
Dolmuchi! How did it go?
I've been waiting without toilet breaks.
Don't stand there like an idiot,
tell me what happened!
What the...?
Why's your face covered in bruises?
It's... I...
It didn't feel right...
I just couldn't do it.
Go tell him I'm sorry for me, all right?
Hey, Dolmuchi!
Hey!
That bastard...
That wicked bitch must've sensed it.
When the butcher got there,
she was already gone.
How far can a pregnant girl go?
Our people are on it. We'll find her soon.
Please forgive me, master!
It won't... happen again!
Mum, you know what,
maybe I should go
join the bandits in the mountains.
What are you yapping on about?
Thieves don't go to heaven.
You don't know how the world works now.
There's a saying,
'united, you are thieves,
divided, you are people.'
Everyone in this country
is a thief of some kind.
Why not us, too?
He's right about that.
We cannot survive just by being good.
The bandit base is in Mt. Jiri,
I heard it's heaven on earth.
Have you all gone mad?
No matter how bad things get,
you gotta play the hand you're dealt.
Your late father always said,
'know your place in life.'
Dolmuchi, are you home?
What brings you here so late?
Who are you?
What's going on?
What are you doing?
Please stop!
Raise him up!
You incompetent bastard!
That bitch in the temple,
where is she now?
I dunno, how could I know that?
Son!
Mother!
He's awake!
Knock that bastard out!
Come out!
Son of a bitch!
Die already!
Tenacious bastard!
Probably dead?
Let's leave!
It can't be...
Mum...
Open your eyes.
Mum.
Please wake up.
Mum...
Gok-ji, wake up!
Sis, please open your eyes.
No...
Mum...
Gok-ji...
How dare he show up here?
How is he still alive?
Go stop that bastard! Stop him!
Buddy, we were just following our orders.
Please!
You didn't have to go so far!
Someone bring the police!
Who is disturbing the wake?
Who the fuck?
Who might you be?
Oh, it's you!
You ordered my family killed.
Executions cannot be carried out
without due process,
you know that.
A humble butcher doesn't
go on a rampage without a motive.
See yourself out.
Butchers are the descendants of barbarians,
they're known to commit serious crimes.
Why do those brutes need
a reason for anything?
Your sister-in-law disappeared
a day after your brother's death.
No reason for that, either?
It's not proper for
a pregnant woman to attend a funeral,
so she was sent to temple.
But,
your men are out searching for her,
why is that?
I don't know if the baby is a boy or girl,
but if she vanishes,
you would become the sole heir.
Should we believe this is
all just a coincidence?
I believe it's somehow related
to the butcher's rampage.
Please open it.
Master Jo, are you ridiculing me?
What should I fill it in With?
Gold, jewels, or money,
I'll fill it with whatever you desire.
He will be executed right away,
won't need to worry anymore.
Kneel, prisoner!
What the hell?
We were sent by Master Jo.
We're here to offer you a chance to live.
He wishes you to finish the job.
What say you?
Will you find the bitch and
kill her or die right here?
I asked you a question!
If you intend to kill me, then do it.
But give Jo my fucking message.
I'll come back as a ghost
and have my revenge.
He looks like a fiend,
but speaks the truth.
Hope you get your wish.
What the...
Do it right.
Wait, I didn't hit him hard enough.
There you go.
His head's rock hard.
Look here!
Go prepare a feast for
our distinguished guest!
Who the fuck does he think he is?
Do it yourself.
Listen to the filth from
that mouth of hers.
Doesn't even rise in greeting.
Watch your mouth when addressing a noble!
You watch it!
So great to see you.
Look at this.
This is extremely rare and expensive,
I brought it just for you.
Keep it.
If someone gives you a gift,
you should thank him,
or you know...
What the fuck was that?
Life isn't just about surviving,
we love and stuff too...
Cut the shit!
Look at this fat pig in heat.
Go wash yourself for once.
You smell like rotting fertilizer.
Wait!
Look here, I got another!
So he's the one?
Water...
Hey idiot!
Don't drink the whole river!
Didn't you have a death wish?
Gonna drink to death?
Come, if you want to live like a man.
Act 3: A New World
Have you been well?
Who is that girl?
Mind your business.
Daddy!
What took you so long? We've been waiting.
Are you hungry?
Give her a hand.
Are you okay?
Who the fuck is that?
Who the fuck?
Brats! Go play over there!
Goddamned little buggers.
Fuck you! No flat-chested
bitch tells us what to do!
Flat-chested bitch!
You little bastards!
Stop right there!
- Fuck you!
- I'll crack your head!
Fatten your titties first!
This is how 18-year old Dolmuchi
came to join the Chusul clan in Mt. Jiri.
As one of the oldest clans in Joseon,
they're proud of the outlaw heritage
that sides with the weak.
Comprised of those shunned
and rejected by society,
they despised greed and unfair authority,
loathed those who
favored social status over ability...
Perfect!
And disdained those who
valued the dead more than the living.
He must've been rich, eh?
But not all who shunned
the world could join the clan.
One had to be chosen.
Just one recommendation
was allowed per branch annually,
and the captain made the final call.
But as with all rules,
exceptions were made.
For the final candidate to become a member,
he had to meet three conditions.
First, his eyes had to be clear.
Second, he must possess a strong will.
And third, distinction was mandatory.
We are all
descendants of our forefather Dankun,
and as such, we are all
brothers and sisters.
But at some point,
the strong began to oppress the weak,
and the rich stole from the poor,
thereby ending our sacred brotherhood.
We will right the wrongs in this world,
you and me!
We will give the poor what
we take from the rich,
fight alongside the weak,
and rebuild the brotherhood!
Do you believe that we can
build this new world?
Yes.
Do you believe that the souls of
the oppressed stand by us?
Mum, please wake up.
Sis, please open your eyes.
Yes.
Will you join us in accomplishing our work?
Heaven and earth bear witness,
you are now one of us.
Get up.
Your name is now 'Dochi'.
It means 'inversion..
No matter how smart and able you are,
one mustn't trade benevolence for anything.
Even if you lack the smarts,
be a good person.
Yes.
No sucker punch this time. C'mere!
Great to have you.
Let's welcome him.
You came a long way!
Live a worthy life.
He looks tough enough.
I kinda like him now.
Halt!
What happened here?
We were... ambushed...
by bandits...
When did it happen? Where did they go?
There...
All the horsemen will go after the bandits,
and the rest guard the tributes!
- Got it?
- Yes, sir!
I can't feel my face.
My balls...
So friggin' cold!
Get up! Hurry!
Buddy! Get the hell up.
Well now, I fell asleep.
You fat pig,
how can you snore while on the job?
The ground was nice and comfy.
Nice day for a hunt, ain't it?
Come on down!
Be careful.
Come down slowly.
Look at me being cute.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Was it hard coming down? Lose some weight.
I was... tripped!
Yo, baldy. This isn't your bed.
Wake up kid, all the elders are up.
Bud, just chill.
I'm a walking shitstorm.
Holy shit...
I apologize if I offend you,
but even a mutt will
laugh at your puny dick.
I feel terrible.
I dunno why you're taking
the long way around.
Why don't you two unload the litter?
I ache all over.
Did you hear me? Unload them!
Are you deaf? She's got aches!
My dear Ma-hyang's talking!
Right?
What? What do you want?
I took a bath today.
They're just cannon fodder,
no need to show off your strength.
Let's unload!
I won't kill you, don't you worry.
Topknot is my inheritance!
I'd rather...
...die!
Death wish?
That's not very honorable.
By any chance,
are you Mt. Jiri's...
Do... Dochi?
Dochi
It's been two years since Dochi was reborn.
Push a little more!
It's a boy!
Absorbing the life force of a newborn,
he has let go of his tragic past,
and became an indispensable figure.
But growth and pain go hand-in-hand.
Witnessing the death of
Jung-sim at childbirth,
who married Jo Su-in as
a bartered bride at 14,
left an unforgettable scar on Dochi's mind,
just like the burn on his head.
For attempting to take a life for pay,
you lost your family.
Us butchers...
we're destined to slaughter,
and follow orders.
My family's deaths aren't my fault!
It's not your fault?
The servants you killed at the wake,
how did they deserve that fate?
The act of killing should only be allowed
as a last resort to saving
the people from harm.
Innocent lives were lost
for your personal greed!
No, of course not!
That wasn't my fault!
Everything in life is interconnected,
like a spider's web.
It's no one's fault.
Free yourself from the
restraints surrounding you.
Cut and eliminate
the source of your inner torment.
After two years of training patiently,
Dochi became infamous,
whose name sent chills
down the nobles' spines.
In Joseon society,
all body hair had to be groomed,
a custom of their forefathers.
The act of cutting off a topknot,
a symbol of masculinity,
Challenged the fundamental
social values of society.
But for him,
it was nothing but a fun new hobby.
Mother!
People believed Dochi was
a descendant of barbarians
due to his hairstyle, or lack thereof.
It made him notorious.
- Flawless!
- Amazing!
Master.
Two years since Dochi's rebirth,
Jo Yoon's wealth and
power outgrew that of his father,
thanks to full support of the new governor.
Historians regard this as
the first private-public enterprise.
On a bad-crop year,
the government issued relief rice,
which had to be repaid with
interest in the following harvest.
Nice and heavy!
The relief rice was mixed
with bran or sand,
or soaked with water to
increase its weight.
But the repayment was only in rice.
Jo easily obtained the records of people
who couldn't repay.
Joseon was known to value
the pen over the sword,
but over-reliance on wealth
would be its downfall.
As Jo obtained the records,
the local office sent out officers
to those who couldn't repay,
and harassed the citizens mercilessly.
You can't demand repayment so suddenly!
Let go! Worthless trash!
Grab him!
After the storm swept through...
Why don't I ask my master for help?
Jo loaned rice without interest
if they gave land papers as collateral.
Take your time paying it back.
Thank you, thank you so much, sir!
He's our savior!
Heaven sent him to us!
The illiterate people drew
a line on their IOU's
without understanding the terms.
These Signatures' would
play a crucial role later.
One year later...
Have you been well, sir?
Thanks for coming so far.
It is my time to pay you all back.
How long has it been?
Your days of hardship are over.
As the country was going through
a financial crisis,
the officers haven't been
paid for several years...
Buddy, what are you doing on my land?
So they repaid his altruism
with absolute obediance.
It's my land now!
Understand?
How is this fair?
Having lost their land overnight,
they went to the governor
to report the unjust...
Punish those sons of bitches!
One!
Two!
Over the span of a year,
they lost their lands,
and became slaves of Lord Jo,
as their IOU's stated.
Jo Yoon soon became the owner of
over 20 km, or half of Naju land.
The citizens began calling
him 'the land demon..
These are new property
documents that I acquired.
They're all under your name,
please have a look.
Father.
It's been two years since
Su-in passed away.
For our family's future,
I believe its time to appoint
the new family heir.
What do you think?
Any news...
of Su-in's wife?
She fled with another
man over two years ago.
Why do you keep asking for her?
Are you really asking me for a reason?
You really think I don't
know what you've done?
Pardon me for saying so,
I heard that delusions and suspicions
might drive you to an early grave.
For your health's sake,
please give up false hope.
You worthless bastards!
Plow the entire length!
Get the fuck up and get to work!
Over here!
Get up!
We were just passing by,
may this humble monk ask
you a few questions?
This might sound silly,
this land is too salty
to cultivate anything,
why do you work the field?
I just feel like it.
Even if it's useless,
it's better than letting it waste away.
At times... it is wiser to let things be.
Your faith must've led you
to take too much interest
in other's affairs.
I'll take your words into consideration.
Act 4: Save the People
That motherfucker!
For someone who once held public office,
how could he be so merciless?
Those who've tasted money thirst for more,
and public officials are the worst.
A beatdown will do.
In addition, with Jo Yoon's full support,
his seven henchmen gamble
and act as loan sharks,
increasing the pain and
suffering of the poor.
I have also heard of his atrocities.
His combat skills are
without equal in Joseon,
and he can easily defeat
ten men all by himself.
But as a bastard, he
couldn't attain a high rank.
He has the power of steel in him.
Born in the year of tiger,
he's fated to become a powerful leader,
but the evil energy surrounding
his soul will lead him...
To have blood on his hands all his life!
We gotta slap his fate
into place and set him straight.
So, what do you want to do?
Do we hit him or not?
He's got the martial arts chops,
and fate is on his side -
he ain't an easy target.
I'll do it.
Give me a week. I'll
come back with his head.
Can't allow it.
Your grudge can't be our motivation.
You need to sit this one out.
Why?
Damn it!
Fuck grudges!
Let me fucking do this!
Man, that temper!
Who do you think you are?
We treated you with
respect, you little shit!
I ain't so little, you shit!
I'm 20 this year!
Bald fuck, and I'm 22,
so respect your elders!
Fucking little shit.
Look at them ignorant bastards.
Boy.
We didn't come here to serve your agenda.
- Sit.
- Sit down!
Watch it, buddy.
Let's do what we've always done.
Let's vote.
This job cannot be done.
We hit him!
There are other, easier jobs.
It's unanimous then.
I was getting restless.
It must be our time to hit the jackpot.
And your time to face him.
Catch that thief!
Stop him!
Stop right there!
There is a warehouse
near Youngsanpo district
that stores grain to be paid as tax.
Get caught while stealing the grain.
In the meantime, you
forge a courthouse seal.
Why me?
Let's say I did that, then what?
Small brush.
One of us needs to
infiltrate the governor's office.
Who?
People are furious at
the Naju governor too,
who's in league with Jo Yoon.
Our ultimate goal
is to take back the land and the rice,
and return them to the people.
I'm from the court of justice,
I need to see the governor.
Ever heard of Lord Jo Won-suk?
He's an incredibly wealthy noble,
and famous in our region.
Then what he says is true.
If he's so wealthy,
he has to be bandits' prime target.
Bandits?
Did you know
your predecessor was killed by
bandits two years ago?
Yes, of course.
He's one of them.
After two years of investigation,
we finally caught him.
The morning is bright,
meet on Spring Equinox day.
After a lengthy interrogation,
we found out that this letter for 'morning'
actually signifies Lord Jo's residence.
That is quite peculiar.
We intercepted this message from
a thief a few days ago.
It is the same.
Isn't today...
the Spring Equinox?
You fools!
You think you decoded our...
According to our investigation,
the ones targeting Lord Jo are
bandits from Mt. Jiri
and Northern province.
We do not yet know where
the Northern bandits are.
Have you heard anything?
Not a damn thing.
Since he claims to know
the base of Mt. Jiri bandits,
we'll coordinate a joint assault
if you give us your men.
As you wish.
Time's running out, we must alert Lord Jo.
My men are en route to his residence.
Here we are.
This is officer Choi from the courthouse.
And this is Lord Jo's son, Yoon.
Pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
These are my personal guards.
They were all military officers,
so bandits are no match for them.
You mustn't underestimate your enemies.
In any case, since your men
are versed in military tactics,
our plan will go smoothly.
I sense a hint of sarcasm.
Could you be implying
that you're not prepared?
Do I sound so obvious?
I'm just being comical.
You're wicked, then. This
isn't a time for jokes.
Master.
We have some guests, sir.
Good to see you all.
With them by my side, I feel safe already.
Do you agree? Aren't they magnificent?
Again, never put personal
vendettas ahead of the plan.
Promise me.
They don't quite instill confidence in me.
Now that my men are here and
we're running out of time,
I'll brief you on the plan.
As you know, the bandits
want grains and jewels.
Your men can hide here for an ambush,
and my men will wait inside the house.
Whoever spots the bandits
first should signal.
Remember this.
We're not here for a killing spree.
We need them alive.
Wait.
In case something goes wrong,
I'll assign two of my men
to look after father.
Of course, whatever you want.
Master.
Come in.
What is it?
Master, are you feeling well?
Who are you?
Master Jo,
I feel rather offended.
How could you not remember me?
I was expecting a clan,
but it's just you?
I guess you're not the listening type.
You remember the girl at the temple?
Your sister-in-law.
I was gonna kill her,
but I was quite lonely, so I kept her.
I took you for a butcher with a long life,
but you walked right through
the gateway to hell.
There's only one way to find out.
Thought your street fighting skills
would be enough?
Where's the girl?
She gave birth to a tough little bastard.
You heard me right.
He's such a strong kid,
his balls are already double your head,
motherfucker!
Come take your rice!
Come to city hall!
Get your rice!
There's no time! Please hurry!
Father, this'll feed us for months!
There's only one reason
why you're still breathing.
Once we leave, give back all
the lands Jo Yoon stole.
If not, we'll break every
bone in your body,
and gut you alive.
Yes, sir.
Please let me live. I'll
do everything you ask.
What brings you here, Master Jo?
Are you from the capital precinct?
We are indeed.
Has a rider passed through here?
That's news to me.
We've been stationed here since 11 PM,
and we haven't seen anyone.
Can you tell me why
that horse is breathing so hard?
Be calm, young man.
Put your sword away.
I knew I sensed some foul spirits,
you must be the bandits.
The fog will be heavy.
If he comes within view,
get ready to fire.
Don't forget.
Where are your manners?
Topknots are for married men.
Cowering away is your only chance to live.
I'll count to 3,
so run like hell.
Got it?
Big words for someone
who can't even defend himself.
Perhaps you'll do better in hell.
One!
Two!
Three!
Ignorant ones are always the strongest.
It's fun to kill, isn't it?
Should the master leave home,
while the bandits are around?
Not bad for bait, huh?
Why are you all so weak?
Carry two at a time to
balance your balls! Hurry!
Take this!
Where's the captain and everyone?
They should be here.
That's true. Something must've happened.
- Here they come.
- Hey!
Ma-hyang!
What happened?
Grab him!
Careful, now.
Where's captain and the others?
I dunno about the captain,
but the others...
they're dead.
- What?
- The compassion of Buddha.
I don't believe this...
Take him to the boat first.
Clear the way!
Move aside!
Tae-gi.
Load the boat!
Take Dochi to Naewon Temple.
And you?
I need to bring back the captain.
What'll you do?
Go on now.
Please...
Hurry!
Let's set sail!
Captain! Captain!
Wake up!
Please, captain.
You still lack discipline.
Why did you come?
One must die quietly.
Brother...
I'll die one way or another.
Grit your teeth,
and walk away.
Just hold on...
Captain.
May you rest with the Buddha.
Act 5: United, You Are People,
Divided, You Are Thieves
Damn you!
I'll ask one more time.
Where are the bandits hiding?
I already told you.
Everyone in this world is a thief.
Some here, some at the capital.
You'd have to be blind to not find one.
Even grannies at the farm
are thieves, got it?
Master Jo.
What should we do now?
The chief could strip me of my position.
You said the bandits gave away rice
in front of your office last night?
Listen carefully!
Whoever received the rice from the bandits,
return every ounce of it by sunset.
Those who do not comply
are allies of the bandits,
and will be punished.
What will you do?
Anyone going back?
If we unite and hold out,
what can he do? He can't kill us all.
No one should return any rice, okay?
I was gonna return it, master!
Please! Father! Father!
Take care of the kids!
I see that you're not afraid to die.
Life and death are one.
How could I be afraid?
The compassion of Buddha.
Let's see how much of
that you truly believe.
Where is your base of operations?
What are you doing?
You monks appreciate even
the most insignificant lives.
Two will fall next, then four.
You mustn't!
Where is your base?
Please don't kill us, master!
Please show us mercy!
It's him you should be begging to!
Your lives depend on his words.
- Monk!
- Monk, save us!
So, I'll ask you again.
Lower your sword!
The power you cannot control
will only harm you!
Lower your sword!
Stop it!
Stop! Enough!
I will not forgive you, even in death!
Mercy and forgiveness are Buddhist values.
You are far from reaching enlightenment.
You're back!
Your late father always said,
'know your place in life.'
We cannot survive just by being good.
- Dochi!
- Brother!
Listen to his thundering cry!
Give it a good push!
Babies need tits.
That's why he's crying.
Give him a tit to suck on.
I'm a little busy, bugger off.
Dae-nam!
Open your eyes!
Find the bald bandit.
You sons of bitches!
Get inside.
It hurts so much...
I'll come right back.
Don't come outside, you hear?
Morn!
Mommy!
Come at me!
You just fucking wait,
I'll skin them alive from head to toe...
The bandits are wiped out thanks to you,
you'll be handsomely rewarded.
Master Jo played a crucial role.
When the regional governor arrives,
I'll speak to him
about your compensation.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
He's not the baby you're looking for.
Please give him to me.
Don't you dare come near!
Please lower your sword.
Come any closer, and I'll slice you open!
No better than a beast!
Even as a concubine's son,
how could you wish ill of your nephew?
For my whole life,
I was no better than a beast to my father.
There's nothing I cannot do.
Shut up!
I should've left you at the whorehouse.
Or beaten you to death.
It was my fault to bring you in
because you have my blood in you.
How dare you?
Why didn't you just leave me?
Why did you keep me alive?
Why did you make me into this?
All I wanted...
was for you to acknowledge me.
What am I to you?
Here is your sentence!
The Mt. Jiri bandits'
crimes are as follows:
First, larceny and the murder of noblemen.
Second, creating public unrest
and distributing stolen property.
Third,
occupying public land without permission.
And finally,
blaming national law to
defend their crimes.
Execute!
I'll kill every one of you!
Ma-hyang!
Get the hell out of my way!
United, we are people,
divided, we are thieves!
You sons of bitches!
Let go of me!
How dare you!
You'll be punished!
Move, move!
Just hold on!
Are you okay? Let me see you.
I'm so sorry.
It's all over now.
You kids all right?
Is it God's will, or the
lotus flower's intention,
when it blooms in the mud?
I will not be so generous anymore,
so just walk away.
Come again?
Look at this douche.
Your arrogance will be the death of you.
Walk away?
You are the sworn enemy of the people.
And my sworn nemesis.
Fine. One more in the grave
won't bother the dead.
Come again?
Someone else died?
I'll free your repulsive face-
from your body.
If any of you...
dare risk your lives to
change your fate, then come!
I'll accept your challenge.
Son of a whore!
Come!
Motherfucker.
I'll cook your liver and
have a drink tonight.
Attain your fucking Buddhahood.